[This drama is a work of fiction.]
[이 드라마는 픽션입니다.]
[Any resemblance to real persons, places, or events is coincidental.]
[실제 인물과 어떤 유사성, 장소나 사건은 우연이다.]
[Scenes with child actors and animals were filmed safely]
[아역 배우와 동물이 등장하는 장면 무사히 촬영됐습니다]
[under professional supervision.]
[전문적인 감독 하에.]
[One year later]
[1년 후]
My part in this story is over.
이 이야기에서 내 역할은 끝났습니다.
Deep down, I knew all along.
깊이는 줄곧 알고 있었습니다.
From the start, I was just a side character, following someone else's script,
저는 처음부터 그냥 사이드 캐릭터였는데, 다른 사람의 스크립트를 따르면서,
caught in a web spun by the people on top.
위에 있는 사람들이 만든 거미줄에 걸렸습니다.
Inside that hell,
그 지옥 속에서
the worthless dream I carried
내가 짊어진 쓸모없는 꿈
didn't stand a chance.
기회가 없었습니다.
Pull yourself together.
함께 힘을 모아보세요.
Even so, in that hell...
그래도 그 지옥에서는...
Pull yourself together!
함께 힘을 모아보세요!
Should my leaving light even the faintest flame,
내가 떠날 때 빛을 비춰야 할까요? 가장 희미한 불꽃이라도
out of this miserable destiny...
이 비참한 운명에서...
For God's sake, pull yourself together.
제발 힘을 모아주세요.
that alone would've made it all worthwhile.
그것만으로도 모든 것이 가치가 있었을 것입니다.
No.
아니요.
Please...
제발...
Sang Ah.
상아.
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Simply sharing the same stage
단순히 같은 무대를 공유하는 것
[Final Episode] was exciting and such a privilege.
[최종회] 정말 흥미롭고 특권이었습니다.
Performing with her in particular,
특히 그녀와 함께 공연하는 것은
I've received so many wonderful sparks of motivation...
나는 너무나 많은 놀라운 불꽃을 받았습니다. 동기부여...
[Avoid mentions of the late Hwang Jeong Won] My question is for actress Chu Sang Ah.
[故 황정원 언급 자제] 제 질문은 배우 추상아님께 입니다.
While shooting, one of the film's clips
촬영하는 동안 영화의 클립 중 하나
got confused for actual leaked material,
실제 유출된 자료로 인해 혼란스러워졌습니다.
and it became a whole thing.
그리고 그것은 완전한 것이 되었습니다.
What was going through your mind at the time?
그 당시 당신의 마음속에는 어떤 생각이 들었나요?
Not easy, honestly.
솔직히 쉽지는 않습니다.
[Four Seasons]
[사계절]
I comforted myself by thinking it just proved how convincing my performance was.
방금 증명된 것 같아 위로를 했어 내 성과가 얼마나 설득력이 있었는지.
On top of that, it gave the movie free publicity,
게다가, 그 영화는 무료로 홍보됐어요
so we tried tracking down who was behind it.
그래서 우리는 배후가 누구인지 추적해 보았습니다.
[Actress Chu Sang Ah] The studio tried to give that person a bonus,
[배우 추상아] 스튜디오에서는 그 사람에게 보너스를 주려고 했는데요,
but they must've gotten nervous because nobody ever owned up.
하지만 그 사람들 긴장했나봐 왜냐하면 아무도 소유한 적이 없기 때문입니다.
Appreciate the response.
답변 감사드립니다.
Would it be okay to squeeze in one more?
하나 더 쑤셔넣어도 괜찮을까요?
Of course, seems like there's more. Please, go on.
물론 더 있는 것 같습니다. 계속하세요.
Much appreciated. Just one more thing.
정말 감사합니다. 한 가지만 더요.
That intimate scene between the two women was absolutely stunning...
두 여자의 은밀한 장면 정말 놀라웠어요...
Hell of a job out there.
정말 좋은 직업이군요.
Loved the movie.
영화를 좋아했습니다.
And getting into the festival, that's huge.
그리고 축제에 참여하는 것은 엄청난 일입니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Couldn't have done it without you.
당신 없이는 할 수 없었을 것입니다.
By the way,
그런데,
I read you booked your next project.
다음 프로젝트를 예약하셨다는 소식을 들었습니다.
That's great news.
좋은 소식이군요.
You seem to be doing well too.
당신도 잘 지내고 있는 것 같군요.
Son Guk Won's campaign brought me on board.
손국원님의 캠페인이 저를 참여하게 만들었습니다.
With the presidential race coming up fast, things are only going to pile up from here.
대선 경선이 빠르게 다가오면서 여기서부터 일이 쌓일 것입니다.
Nice. I'll be cheering you on.
멋진. 응원하겠습니다.
We should get moving now.
이제 움직여야 해요.
I appreciate you showing up.
나타나주셔서 감사합니다.
Look after yourself.
자신을 돌보세요.
Sang Ah.
상아.
I've got something
뭔가 갖고 있어
to run by you.
너한테 달려가려고.
Let's get to your Monday morning headlines.
월요일 아침 헤드라인을 살펴보겠습니다.
With the heated showdown between Doyak Party's Son Guk Won
열띤 대결과 함께 도약당 손국원 사이
and Changjo Party's Gu Hong Seo still raging,
그리고 창조당 서구홍은 여전히 ​​분노하고 있다
the latest polls
최신 여론조사
put Candidate Son at the top in approval ratings.
아들 후보 넣기 지지율 상위권에 있습니다.
[The assemblyman has confirmed it]
[의원님이 확인하셨습니다]
[Campaign Manager Lee Chan Yong]
[캠페인 매니저 이찬용]
[22nd Presidential Election Debate]
[22대 대선 토론회]
Reconsider this, sir.
다시 생각해보세요, 선생님.
Voters today are levelheaded and sharp.
오늘날 유권자들은 분별력 있고 예리합니다.
Some tearjerker bit about a vintage watch isn't fooling anyone.
빈티지 시계에 대한 눈물 흘리는 이야기 누구도 속이지 않습니다.
Changjo doesn't have proof regardless,
창조는 어차피 증거가 없어,
so no matter what they hurl at me,
그러니 그들이 나에게 무슨 말을 던지더라도
brush it off as groundless smear tactics.
근거없는 비방전술로 무시하세요.
If I may, sir, just a second.
선생님, 잠시만 기다려 주세요.
Sure, that buys us time today,
물론이죠, 오늘은 시간을 벌 수 있는 일이죠,
but it won't turn the tide in our direction.
하지만 그렇다고 해서 흐름이 우리 방향으로 바뀌지는 않을 것입니다.
Winning this election
이번 선거에서 승리
takes a narrative that hits people in the gut.
사람들의 직감을 강타하는 이야기를 취합니다.
Once we can predict
일단 예측할 수 있게 되면
what Changjo's throwing at us, like today,
오늘처럼 창조가 우리에게 던지는 것은
dropping our counter at precisely the right beat
카운터를 내려놓고 정확한 박자에 맞춰
makes your integrity
당신의 진실성을 만든다
and patriotism land even harder.
애국심은 더욱 어려워집니다.
Fair enough.
충분합니다.
Nobody knows their playbook better than you,
자신의 플레이북을 당신만큼 잘 아는 사람은 없습니다.
considering you were one of them.
당신이 그들 중 하나라는 것을 고려하면.
Sir.
선생님.
Tonight will be the spark
오늘 밤이 불꽃이 될 거야
that sets off our upward trajectory from here.
그것은 여기에서 우리의 상승 궤도를 시작합니다.
Your loyalty, I can't count on.
당신의 충성심은 믿을 수 없습니다.
But that mind of yours, I believe in.
하지만 나는 당신의 그 마음을 믿습니다.
I appreciate that.
감사합니다.
Leave the timing to me.
타이밍은 나에게 맡겨주세요.
[22nd Presidential Election Debate]
[22대 대선 토론회]
Out of every candidate in this race,
이번 경선의 모든 후보자 중에서
not one has less moral credibility than Candidate Son.
누구도 도덕적 신뢰성이 낮지 않습니다 아들 후보보다.
Between the Daeyang Fund slush accounts,
대양펀드 비자금 계좌 사이
corporate kickbacks, and abuse of power,
기업 리베이트 및 직권 남용,
that's only what we already know about.
그것은 우리가 이미 알고 있는 것뿐입니다.
Imagine what else will turn up once we start digging.
또 어떤 일이 일어날지 상상해 보세요 일단 파기 시작하면.
Is this really the person we'd trust
이 사람이 정말 우리가 믿을 만한 사람인가요?
to carry this nation on his shoulders?
이 나라를 그의 어깨에 짊어지려고?
Those recordings from the general election
총선 녹화
were confirmed as forgeries. Didn't we already settle that?
위조된 것으로 확인되었습니다. 우리는 이미 그 문제를 해결하지 않았나요?
What makes you keep pushing falsehoods
무엇이 계속 거짓을 강요하게 만드는가
with nothing to back them up?
백업할 게 아무것도 없나요?
You plan on dodging this all the way to the finish?
넌 이걸 피할 계획이야 끝까지?
[Transcript of Daeyang Fund] What we've gathered alone is
[대양펀드 성적표] 우리가 혼자서 모은 것은
more than enough for a warrant.
영장을 발부받기에 충분합니다.
There isn't a doubt in my mind
내 생각엔 의심의 여지가 없어
that you're lying to our faces.
당신이 우리 면전에서 거짓말을 하고 있다고요.
Should I be mistaken,
내가 착각해야 할까,
I'll resign from this race
나는 이번 경주에서 물러날 거야
and surrender everything I own.
그리고 내가 가진 모든 것을 내놓으십시오.
So what are you willing to stake?
그렇다면 당신은 무엇을 걸고자 합니까?
My grandfather carried this watch
할아버지가 이 시계를 갖고 다녔어요
through the independence movement in the 1930s.
1930년대 독립운동을 통해
It's been our family's most sacred possession ever since.
우리 가족의 일이었어 그 이후로 가장 신성한 소유물.
Can you see the blood on it?
거기에 피 보이시나요?
Should I
내가
really be the symbol of corruption,
정말 부패의 상징이군요
some fossil dragging Korean politics backwards,
한국 정치를 거꾸로 끌고 가는 일부 화석,
then I'll walk away from this election today.
그렇다면 저는 오늘 이번 선거에서 물러나겠습니다.
- Yet. - Yet
- 아직. - 아직
- Every single day, I hold this watch - every single day,
- 매일매일 이 시계를 들고 있어요 - 매일,
- and remind myself that - I hold this watch
-그리고 나 자신에게 상기시켜줘 - 나는 이 시계를 갖고 있다
- and remind myself that... - our forebears built this country
- 그리고 나 자신에게 상기시켜주세요... - 우리의 조상들이 이 나라를 건설했습니다
through blood and sacrifice.
피와 희생을 통해.
our forebears built this country
우리의 조상들이 이 나라를 건설했습니다
Every fiber of my being
내 존재의 모든 섬유질
- has gone... - Every fiber of my being
- 가버렸어... - 내 존재의 모든 섬유질
- into serving this nation. - has gone into serving this nation.
- 이 나라에 봉사하기 위해. - 이 나라를 위해 봉사했습니다.
But
하지만
if baseless attacks
근거 없는 공격이라면
and character assassination are your game, be my guest.
캐릭터 암살이 당신의 게임입니다. 내 손님이 되어주세요.
Let the citizens of this nation decide what's real.
이 나라 국민들이여 무엇이 진짜인지 결정하세요.
In that spirit,
그런 의미에서
I'm staking this seat,
나는 이 자리에 앉을 거야,
[22nd Presidential Election Debate] every last thing I own,
[22대 대선 토론회] 내가 소유한 모든 것,
along with...
함께...
a century of my family's devotion
우리 가족의 헌신의 100년
to this country.
이 나라로.
Well then, Candidate Gu,
그럼 구 후보님,
prepared to step down?
물러날 준비가 됐나요?
Wait.
기다리다.
Just a moment.
잠시만요.
All nine minutes of Candidate Gu Hong Seo's
서구홍 후보의 9분 전체
initiative segment have been exhausted.
이니셔티브 세그먼트가 소진되었습니다.
Candidate Son Guk Won,
손국원 후보,
the floor is yours for your initiative debate.
귀하의 주도적 토론을 위한 자리는 귀하의 것입니다.
[TV debate heats up over allegations] Thank you.
[TV토론은 의혹으로 뜨거워지고 있다] 감사합니다.
That was incredible, sir.
정말 대단했어요, 선생님.
Congratulations.
축하해요.
Congratulations, sir.
축하드립니다.
The watch moment peaked at over 40% viewership.
시청률은 40%가 넘는 최고 시청률을 기록했습니다.
And the whole thing buried the ethics scandal completely.
그리고 모든 것이 묻혀버렸어 윤리 스캔들을 완전히.
I figured it was old-school,
구식인 줄 알았는데,
but the classics never fail.
하지만 고전은 결코 실패하지 않습니다.
Born strategist, born showman.
타고난 전략가, 타고난 쇼맨.
Director,
이사
tonight went perfectly. Why are we having this conversation again?
오늘 밤은 완벽하게 갔다. 우리는 왜 또 이런 대화를 나누는 걸까요?
If I rush the insurance reform play,
보험 개혁을 서두르면
I'm just loading the gun for Gu Hong Seo.
서구홍에게 총을 장전하는 중이에요.
And that gossip floating around the trading floors,
그리고 떠다니는 그 가십
that I'll hand you
내가 너에게 줄게
WR Life shares once I'm sworn in,
내가 선서하면 WR Life가 공유합니다.
you don't think the Changjo Party planted that?
그걸 창조당이 심은 게 아닌가?
Look.
바라보다.
Hey, get it together!
이봐, 함께하자!
Sir.
선생님.
You seem to have a short memory about everything I did
당신은 기억력이 짧은 것 같아요 내가 한 모든 일에 대해
to build you up and carry you here.
너를 세워 여기까지 데려가려고.
Where you go from here is still in my hands.
네가 여기서 어디로 가는지는 아직 내 손안에 있다.
Don't forget that.
그것을 잊지 마세요.
One wrong turn from me,
내가 한 번 잘못 방향을 틀었나,
and you're off the edge. It's that simple.
당신은 위기에 처해 있습니다. 정말 간단해요.
Chairman Kwon could go any day now,
권 회장은 이제 언제든지 갈 수 있다,
so quit stalling
그러니 그만둬
and get the inheritance law amendment lined up
그리고 상속법 개정안을 준비하세요
before you even sit down in that chair.
그 의자에 앉기도 전에요.
We clear?
클리어?
Who does she think she's playing...
그녀는 자신이 누구와 놀고 있다고 생각하는가...
Want a drink?
한잔 원하시나요?
So,
그래서,
that thing you said you needed to discuss,
당신이 논의해야 한다고 말한 것
what is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
I'm going to pry Lee Yang Mi
이양미를 캐러갈거야
off of Son's back.
아들의 등에서.
Lee Yang Mi's dropped the mask,
이양미가 마스크를 떨어뜨렸어요
and the cracks between them are already showing.
그리고 그 사이의 균열 이미 보여주고 있습니다.
Son already knows that even if he wins,
아들은 자신이 이기더라도
he's just going to be Lee Yang Mi's puppet,
그는 그냥 이양미의 꼭두각시가 될 거야,
so I'll work on him
그래서 내가 그 사람을 위해 노력할게
and build a financial cushion to replace Lee Yang Mi's bankroll
금융쿠션을 구축하고 이양미 자금 대체
when the moment's right.
적절한 순간에.
You're deep inside both Son's and Lee Yang Mi's circles right now.
넌 두 아들의 깊숙한 곳에 있어 그리고 지금 이양미 서클.
You're willing to risk all that? To do what?
그 모든 위험을 감수할 의향이 있나요? 무엇을 하려고?
If I don't move now, she's going to eat me alive all over again.
지금 움직이지 않으면 그녀는 다시 나를 산 채로 잡아먹을 거야.
I can't let her ruin
그녀를 망치게 놔둘 수는 없어
what I've spent my whole life chasing.
내가 평생을 쫓아다녔던 것.
And you
그리고 당신은
can't keep getting stepped on either.
계속 밟을 수도 없고.
And I...
그리고 나는...
I want you back too.
나도 당신이 돌아왔으면 좋겠어요.
After all of it,
결국,
I thought I'd lost you for good.
난 당신을 영원히 잃었다고 생각했어요.
But that year without you,
하지만 그 해에는 당신이 없었어요
I realized just how much of you was in me.
나는 당신이 내 안에 얼마나 많은지 깨달았습니다.
Getting hit, falling down,
맞고, 넘어지고,
but knowing you were somewhere out there, looking the same direction...
하지만 당신이 저 바깥 어딘가에 있다는 걸 알았을 때 같은 방향을 보고 있는 중...
that's what kept me standing.
그것이 나를 계속 서 있게 해준 것입니다.
Yeah...
응...
I guess we really were alike.
아무래도 우리는 정말 비슷했던 것 같아요.
Sleeping alone, waking up alone in this house,
이 집에서 혼자 자고, 혼자 일어나고,
I had the exact same thought.
나도 똑같은 생각을했다.
I was looking too.
나도 찾고 있었어요.
A way to destroy Lee Yang Mi.
이양미를 파멸시키는 방법.
There's someone I need to see first.
먼저 만나야 할 사람이 있어요.
I'm meeting Assemblyman Choi from the Changjo Party
최 의원을 만나러 갑니다 창조당 소속
and giving him something he can't walk away from.
그리고 그에게 무언가를 주는 것 그는 떠날 수 없습니다.
The Doyak Party's mastermind never picked up my calls,
도약당의 주모자 내 전화를 전혀 받지 않았어,
and now you come to me. What an honor.
이제 당신은 나에게 옵니다. 정말 영광입니다.
These are original documents
원본 문서입니다
containing part of the testimony
증언의 일부 포함
from a key insider in the Daeyang Fund.
대양펀드 핵심 인사
Son doesn't even know this exists,
아들은 이것이 존재하는지조차 모릅니다.
so he can't fight it,
그래서 그는 싸울 수 없어요
and the impact will be enormous.
그리고 그 영향은 엄청날 것입니다.
If you'd played this during last year's election,
이 게임을 플레이했다면 작년 선거 당시
the whole outcome could've been different.
전체 결과가 달라졌을 수도 있습니다.
Why hold it back until now?
왜 지금까지 보류하고 있나요?
Let's just say I was keeping it for a day like this.
내가 그것을 지키고 있었다고 가정해보자. 이런 날을 위해.
I play the long game too.
나도 긴 게임을 한다.
That election was never the endgame.
그 선거는 결코 최종전이 아니었습니다.
That takes real nerve.
정말 용기가 필요합니다.
Regardless, the files are password-locked.
어쨌든 파일은 비밀번호로 잠겨 있습니다.
Pick the release date with me,
나와 함께 출시 날짜를 선택하세요.
and I'll send over the password.
비밀번호를 보내드리겠습니다.
This is Candidate Gu's handwritten pledge.
구 후보의 자필 공약입니다.
[Changjo Party]
[창조파티]
[I'll guarantee Bang Tae Seop the No. 3 PR slot] Proportional seat number three, it's yours.
[방태섭씨 PR 3위는 제가 보장할게요] 3번 비례의석은 당신의 것입니다.
Under the radar,
레이더 아래서,
but right where the spotlight hits.
그러나 바로 스포트라이트가 비추는 곳입니다.
Understood.
알겠습니다.
I'll be waiting for your call.
당신의 전화를 기다리고 있겠습니다.
Once the Changjo Party takes the bait,
일단 창조당이 미끼를 물면
they'll set it off right on cue,
신호가 오면 바로 시작할 거야,
and when Son's cornered,
그리고 아들이 궁지에 몰렸을 때,
I'll offer to make it go away and cut a deal.
나는 그것을 없애고 거래를 중단하겠다고 제안할 것이다.
This is a copy of the USB
이것은 USB
that Hwang Jeong Won left before she died.
황정원이 죽기 전에 떠났다는 것.
I handed Lee Yang Mi a version
이양미에게 버전을 건네줬어요
with the dashcam footage wiped, the part that proves she's the one
대시캠 영상이 지워진 상태에서 그녀가 그 사람이라는 것을 증명하는 부분
behind Park Jae Sang's death.
박재상의 죽음의 배후.
[Phone records]
[통화 기록]
I cleaned it so thoroughly that even a forensic sweep won't find it.
너무 깨끗하게 청소했어요 법의학 수사를 해도 찾을 수 없을 것입니다.
She has no reason to doubt it.
그녀는 그것을 의심할 이유가 없습니다.
But on this copy,
하지만 이 사본에서는
that dashcam footage is still there.
그 대시캠 영상이 아직도 거기 있어요.
Jeong Won...
정원...
she knew everything.
그녀는 모든 것을 알고 있었습니다.
I was tired of being a coward.
나는 겁쟁이가 되는 것에 지쳤습니다.
This is basically the original of Oh Kwang Jae's list,
이게 기본적으로 원본임 오광재 목록 중
the one that's gone now.
지금은 없어진 것.
[He said he'd introduce me to the big boss who's funding the drama]
[그가 나를 소개해준다고 했어 드라마 자금을 지원하는 상사에게]
I started writing everything down when I was twenty,
나는 모든 것을 적기 시작했다 내가 스무살이었을 때,
before that bastard ever asked me to.
그 새끼가 나한테 달라고 하기 전에 말이야.
I kept going back and forth
계속 왔다 갔다 했어
about just blowing it all open,
그냥 다 열어버리면 되지,
or finding a way to take down those men
아니면 그 사람들을 쓰러뜨릴 방법을 찾는 중
and Lee Yang Mi in one shot.
그리고 이양미까지 한방에.
[I couldn't get away when he grabbed my arm]
[그가 내 팔을 잡았을 때 나는 도망칠 수 없었다]
[No, I didn't even try to run. That's what's so haunting right now]
[아니요, 도망치려고도 하지 않았어요. 그게 바로 지금 정말 잊혀지지 않는 이유]
Are you sure about this?
확실합니까?
The stakes are high.
위험이 높습니다.
You're putting just as much on the line.
당신은 그만큼의 노력을 기울이고 있습니다.
And I trust we won't fail.
그리고 나는 우리가 실패하지 않을 것이라고 믿습니다.
Then all that's left
그럼 남은 건
is turning every man in this diary
이 일기에 있는 모든 사람을 바꾸고 있어
into a financial cushion for Son, to replace Lee Yang Mi's pipeline.
손흥민에게 재정적 쿠션을 제공하고, 이양미 파이프라인 교체.
I saw the article about your son being named heir to the group.
당신 아들에 관한 기사를 봤어요 그룹의 후계자로 지명됩니다.
I was surprised, honestly.
솔직히 놀랐어요.
People don't change easily,
사람은 쉽게 변하지 않아
and those were your own words.
그리고 그것은 당신 자신의 말입니다.
He's your son, but the boy's a lost cause.
그 사람은 당신 아들이에요. 하지만 그 아이는 길을 잃었어요.
Get to the point.
요점을 파악하세요.
Then you remember that day, don't you?
그럼 그날을 기억하지?
The day your son got behind the wheel drunk and hit someone.
네 아들이 술에 취해 운전하던 날 그리고 누군가를 때리세요.
Watch your mouth.
입을 조심하세요.
I happened to be at that same dinner that night
나는 그날 밤 우연히 같은 저녁 식사에 참석했습니다
because of the MK commercial shoot.
MK 광고 촬영 때문에요.
You remember that, right?
그거 기억하지?
Ji Hyuk was drinking, took the car, and hit somebody.
지혁이 술을 마시고 차를 타고 가더니 그리고 누군가를 때리세요.
Get a replacement driver set up right now.
지금 바로 교체 드라이버를 설치하세요.
Find some actor to take the blame,
비난을 받을 배우를 찾으세요.
and buy the witnesses off.
그리고 증인을 매수합니다.
- Get our guys in the prosecution - Back then my life was such a disaster
- 우리 직원들을 검찰에 기소하세요 - 그땐 내 인생이 정말 재앙이었어
- and the police to bury it. Whatever it takes. - that I recorded every phone call.
- 그리고 경찰은 그것을 묻습니다. 무슨 일이 있어도. - 모든 전화 통화를 녹음했습니다.
Got it?
알았나요?
And you were right there next to me, completely wasted,
그리고 당신은 바로 내 옆에 있었어요. 완전히 낭비됐어
ordering the driver swap,
드라이버 교체를 주문하고,
calling his lawyer, and it's all on tape.
그의 변호사에게 전화를 걸면 모든 것이 테이프에 담겨 있습니다.
What do you think happens when this gets out
이게 나오면 무슨 일이 일어날 것 같아요
and you're standing in the court of public opinion?
그리고 당신은 법정에 서있습니다 여론의?
What the hell do you want?
도대체 뭘 원하는 거야?
Some kind of crusade for justice?
정의를 위한 일종의 십자군?
Justice?
정당성?
I don't care about that.
나는 그것에 대해 신경 쓰지 않습니다.
I'm here to shake you down.
나는 당신을 흔들려고 여기에 있습니다.
Don't waste your time
시간을 낭비하지 마세요
tracing the accounts.
계좌를 추적 중입니다.
Fill this with dollars.
이것을 달러로 채워라.
It should fit about a million.
100만 정도는 들어가야 합니다.
[I'm dropping it in five days]
[5일 뒤에 내려놓을 예정이에요]
We just got word that the Changjo Party is getting ready
방금 소식을 받았어요 창조당이 준비 중이라는 소식
to drop something big.
큰 것을 떨어뜨리려고.
What kind of big?
어떤 종류의 큰?
[Doyak Party] We don't have the specifics yet,
[도약파티] 아직 구체적인 내용은 없습니다.
but their leadership is convinced
하지만 그들의 리더십은 확신하고 있어요
that once it breaks, Candidate Gu takes the whole thing.
그건 일단 깨지고, 구 후보가 모든 것을 맡는다.
If we can nail down the timing,
타이밍을 확정할 수 있다면
we can prepare a proper counter.
적절한 카운터를 준비할 수 있어요.
I've dug as far in as I can, even into their inner circle,
할 수 있는 데까지 파고들었어요. 심지어 내부 서클에도
but this is locked down at the very top.
하지만 이것은 맨 위에 잠겨 있습니다.
Nearly impossible to crack.
크랙이 거의 불가능합니다.
Have the press send over this month's issue schedule.
언론에서 보내도록 하세요 이번달 발행일정입니다.
Look for the open dates.
오픈 날짜를 찾아보세요.
Whatever this is, if it's that big,
이게 뭐든 간에, 그렇게 크면
the Changjo Party won't sit on it long.
창조당은 오래 앉아있지 못할 것이다.
Yes, sir. I'll get on it.
네, 선생님. 내가 처리할게.
I'll prep something to bury whatever the Changjo Party puts out.
묻어둘 것 좀 준비할게 창조당이 내놓는 것은 뭐든지.
No. This is above your pay grade.
아니요. 이는 귀하의 급여 등급보다 높습니다.
Secretary Kim,
김비서
loop in Lee Yang Mi's people
이양미 사람들의 루프
and tell them to move. Now.
그리고 움직이라고 하세요. 지금.
With the biggest card they've got in storage.
저장 공간에 있는 가장 큰 카드를 사용합니다.
I swore I'd stop going back to that woman.
나는 그 여자에게 다시는 돌아가지 않겠다고 맹세했습니다.
The leak moved faster than we expected.
누출은 예상보다 빠르게 진행되었습니다.
Let's push it up. Day after tomorrow.
밀어 올리자. 모레.
That fast?
그렇게 빠르나요?
I was thinking mid-month at the earliest, maybe even later.
빠르면 이달 중순을 생각하고 있었는데, 어쩌면 나중에라도.
We have to hit first, before Lee Yang Mi gets her story ready.
먼저 쳐야 하는데, 이양미가 이야기를 준비하기 전에.
If it blindsides us,
그것이 우리의 눈을 멀게 한다면,
Son's scandal gets buried regardless of timing.
손흥민 스캔들은 시기와 상관없이 묻혀진다.
I don't know. I'd need to discuss it.
모르겠어요. 그것에 대해 논의해야 할 것 같아요.
Sir.
선생님.
We lose this window and it's done.
이 창을 잃어버리면 완료됩니다.
It's a race against the clock now.
지금은 시간과의 싸움입니다.
Will you just watch the presidency go up in smoke?
그냥 지켜볼래? 대통령직이 연기가 나나요?
All right.
알았어.
I hear you.
듣고 있어요.
I'll handle the candidate.
후보를 처리하겠습니다.
Jesus.
예수님.
Idiot.
바보.
The woman's voice should come through perfectly clear now.
여자 목소리가 나와야지 이제 완전히 명확해졌습니다.
Yes, Director.
예, 국장님.
It's done.
완료되었습니다.
You didn't leave a trace, did you?
흔적을 남기지 않았죠?
It needs to look like a suicide. No exceptions.
자살처럼 보여야 합니다. 예외는 없습니다.
[News Director Lee Jae Moon]
[이재문 뉴스국장]
This will be
이것은
the biggest story to hit this year.
올해 가장 큰 이야기.
It's done.
완료되었습니다.
You didn't leave a trace, did you?
흔적을 남기지 않았죠?
It needs to look like a suicide. No exceptions.
자살처럼 보여야 합니다. 예외는 없습니다.
I get it. WR's your top advertiser,
알겠습니다. WR이 최고의 광고주입니다.
so this isn't a simple decision.
그래서 이것은 간단한 결정이 아닙니다.
Even with all the risk,
모든 위험을 무릅쓰고
is there a reason for us to run this?
우리가 이것을 실행할 이유가 있나요?
You can pass.
통과할 수 있습니다.
It's a race
경주야
to see who breaks it first,
누가 먼저 깨뜨렸는지 확인하려면
and I can always walk this over to another network.
그리고 난 언제든지 이 부분을 지나갈 수 있어요 다른 네트워크로.
But if I were sitting in your chair,
하지만 내가 당신의 의자에 앉아 있었다면
I'd be prepping the broadcast already.
벌써 방송을 준비하고 있었을 텐데.
By tomorrow, I'll have someone "upstairs" pick up the phone,
내일까지 "위층"에 누군가가 있을 거예요 전화를 받아
call the president of MJN,
MJN 회장에게 전화해
and make it an order from the top.
그리고 위에서부터 주문을 하세요.
And when that happens, you'll be the one
그리고 그런 일이 일어나면 당신이 바로 그 사람이 될 거예요
who let the exclusive slip. That's not a good look.
독점적인 실수를 저지른 사람. 별로 좋은 표정이 아니네요.
How about this?
이건 어때요?
You get the broadcast and the promo ready ahead of time,
방송을 받으시네요 프로모션이 미리 준비되어 있어요
so the second the order drops,
그래서 두 번째 주문이 취소되면
you can fire it off immediately.
즉시 발사할 수 있습니다.
In exchange,
그 대가로
I take the promo footage first.
홍보영상을 먼저 찍습니다.
On the condition nothing leaks to the press.
이 조건에서는 언론에 아무것도 누출되지 않습니다.
That's the deal.
그게 거래입니다.
Fair enough.
충분합니다.
The angle shouldn't just be one person's dirty laundry.
각도가 그냥 있어서는 안 된다. 한 사람의 더러운 빨래.
It should expose the rot in Korea's elite class.
부패를 드러내야합니다 한국의 엘리트 클래스에서.
What do you say?
당신은 무엇을 말합니까?
[The WR Family's Dirty Secrets, Coming Up on MJN 9 News!]
[WR 가문의 더러운 비밀, MJN 9 뉴스에 등장!]
The founding family of WR Group, the third-largest conglomerate in Korea,
WR 그룹의 창립자 가족, 한국에서 세 번째로 큰 대기업,
[WR Director Charged with Murder-for-Hire] is now implicated in a murder-for-hire.
[고용살인 혐의로 기소된 WR 디렉터] 현재 고용 살인 사건에 연루되어 있습니다.
[Hit Ordered Through Broker, Evidence Destroyed] Shocking video evidence has surfaced.
[브로커를 통해 명중 지시, 증거 파기] 충격적인 영상 증거가 드러났습니다.
[Hwang Yong Deok] [Promise kept. Exposé stops at WR]
[황용덕] [약속은 지켰다. Exposé는 WR에서 멈춤]
The founding family of WR Group, the third-largest conglomerate in Korea,
WR 그룹의 창립자 가족, 한국에서 세 번째로 큰 대기업,
is now implicated in a murder-for-hire. Shocking video evidence has surfaced.
는 현재 고용 살인 사건에 연루되어 있습니다. 충격적인 영상 증거가 드러났습니다.
The director of WR Entertainment, who is also the chairman's spouse...
WR 엔터테인먼트 이사, 회장의 배우자이기도 한 사람...
- a Ms. Lee, is alleged to have ordered - This is the 9 o'clock news promo
- 이씨가 주문한 것으로 추정됨 - 9시 뉴스 프로모션입니다
the hit through a broker,
브로커를 통한 히트
- we secured by giving MJN the source material. - and is suspected of tampering
- MJN에게 소스 자료를 제공하여 확보했습니다. - 조작이 의심되는 경우
with evidence to make the scene
사건을 만들 증거를 가지고
look like a suicide.
자살 같은데
Tonight at nine...
오늘 밤 9시...
- What is this? - An MJN exclusive.
- 이게 뭔가요? - MJN 독점.
I don't remember giving any order like this.
나는 이런 명령을 내린 기억이 없다.
The Changjo Party got their hands on this.
창조당이 이에 손을 댔다.
It's CEO Yoon from Daeyang Fund. His testimony, filmed before he died.
대양펀드 윤 대표입니다. 그가 죽기 전에 촬영된 그의 증언.
I'm Yoon Sang Hyun, CEO of Daeyang Fund.
대양펀드 대표 윤상현 입니다.
And it goes public tonight.
그리고 오늘 밤 공개됩니다.
Assemblyman Son Guk Won
손국원 의원
used my fund to build a slush fund,
내 자금을 비자금 조성에 사용했습니다.
and when the truth started closing in,
진실이 가까워지기 시작했을 때
he tried to have me killed.
그는 나를 죽이려고 했습니다.
This is
이것은
the bug they planted in my car.
그들이 내 차에 심은 벌레
And it's proof.
그리고 그것은 증거입니다.
Knew it. You really are a wolf.
알았어. 당신은 정말로 늑대입니다.
This is Lee Yang Mi's playbook, move for move.
이양미님의 플레이북 Move for Move 입니다.
So what's your endgame here?
그렇다면 여기서 최종 게임은 무엇입니까?
Drop Lee Yang Mi and pick me.
이양미 버리고 나를 뽑아라
And once you're in office,
그리고 일단 취임하면,
I want the Senior Secretary for Civil Affairs seat.
나는 수석 비서를 원한다 민정석에.
Once a mad dog, always a mad dog.
한번 미친 개는 영원히 미친 개입니다.
I told you,
내가 말했잖아
I trust your brain,
나는 당신의 두뇌를 믿습니다.
but not your heart.
하지만 당신의 마음은 아닙니다.
Remember that?
그거 기억나?
That nuclear bomb the Changjo Party's holding right now,
그 핵폭탄은 창조당의 것 지금은 보류 중
isn't that the evidence you got from the Shadow during the general election?
그게 당신이 얻은 증거 아닌가요? 총선 기간 동안 그림자로부터?
Your wife was hanging off a cliff,
당신의 아내는 절벽에 매달려 있었습니다
and you still held on to your last card
아직도 마지막 카드를 갖고 있지
for yourself. Tell me, how do I trust a man like that?
자신을 위해. 말해봐, 그런 사람을 어떻게 믿을 수 있니?
You need to trust the choice
당신은 선택을 신뢰해야 합니다
he made when he held that card back.
그는 그 카드를 다시 쥐었을 때 만들었습니다.
Even if he'd played that card,
그 사람이 그 카드를 사용했더라도
it still wouldn't have buried my story.
그래도 내 이야기는 묻히지 않았을 겁니다.
Tae Seop wasn't abandoning me back then.
그때 태섭이가 나를 버린 게 아니었어.
He was protecting my future,
그는 내 미래를 보호하고 있었어
waiting for a moment exactly like today.
오늘과 같은 순간을 기다려요.
Either way,
어느 쪽이든,
I'm not cutting Lee Yang Mi loose.
나는 이양미를 헐뜯는 게 아니다.
And even if I wanted to, I can't.
그리고 내가 원하더라도 할 수 없습니다.
You'll regret this.
당신은 이것을 후회할 것입니다.
Throwing away the small fish to catch the big one?
작은 물고기를 버리고 큰 놈 잡으려고?
If the small fish eats the big fish,
작은 물고기가 큰 물고기를 먹으면
is that still a big fish or a small fish?
아직도 큰 물고기인가요, 아니면 작은 물고기인가요?
You want WR? Then choose me.
WR을 원하시나요? 그럼 나를 선택하세요.
You'll see why soon enough.
그 이유는 곧 알게 될 것입니다.
It's the exact amount Director Lee promised you in slush money.
정확한 금액이에요 이 감독이 비자금으로 약속했어요.
No strings attached. It's clean money.
연결된 문자열이 없습니다. 깨끗한 돈이에요.
MJN is locked and loaded to run the Director Lee Yang Mi story tonight.
MJN이 잠기고 로드되어 실행됩니다. 오늘 밤에는 이양미 감독의 이야기를 들어보겠습니다.
[MJN President Lim Won Guk] When you've made up your mind,
[MJN 임원국 회장] 마음을 정했다면,
call this number.
이 번호로 전화해 보세요.
I believe in your judgment.
나는 당신의 판단을 믿습니다.
Hello, sir. This is Son Guk Won.
안녕하세요, 선생님. 손국원 입니다.
Good evening, everyone.
좋은 저녁입니다, 여러분.
This is the 9 o'clock news.
9시 뉴스입니다.
Our top story tonight involves the country's third-largest conglomerate.
오늘 밤 우리의 주요 기사는 다음과 같습니다. 국내에서 세 번째로 큰 대기업입니다.
The dark secrets of the WR family.
WR 가족의 어두운 비밀.
[WR Ent. Director Accused of Murder] The wife of WR Group Chairman Kwon Se Myeong
[WR 엔터. 감독 살인 혐의] 권세명 WR그룹 회장 부인
and WR Entertainment director, identified only as Ms. Lee,
및 WR 엔터테인먼트 디렉터, 이씨로만 확인되었습니다.
has been named as the real culprit
진짜 범인으로 지목되었습니다
behind the murder of Mr. Park that rocked the nation.
박씨 살해 배후 그것은 나라를 뒤흔들었습니다.
[Arrest Warrant Issued for Director Lee] MJN has obtained the evidence exclusively.
[이 이사에 대한 구속영장 발부] MJN이 독점적으로 증거를 입수했습니다.
Investigators have detained suspect Mr. Cheon,
수사관들이 피의자 천 씨를 구속했습니다.
[Broker MeTuber Choi: Key Link to Ms. Lee] and secured a statement that MeTuber Mr. Choi,
[최미튜버 브로커 : 이씨에게 핵심링크] 그리고 MeTuber 최 씨가
acted under orders from Ms. Lee, a director
이사인 이씨의 지시에 따라 행동
[Statement Secured, Manhunt Underway] - at WR Entertainment, - Yes, Director.
[진술 확보, 수사 진행 중] - WR Entertainment에서 - 네, 감독님.
- who allegedly gave the kill order. - It's done.
-살해 명령을 내린 것으로 추정되는 사람. - 끝났어요.
- A full investigation is now underway. - You didn't leave a trace, did you?
- 현재 전체 조사가 진행 중입니다. - 흔적을 남기지 않았죠?
[CCTV Audio Restored] It needs to look like a suicide. No exceptions.
[CCTV 오디오 복원됨] 자살처럼 보여야 합니다. 예외는 없습니다.
An anonymous tip has surfaced
익명의 제보가 나타났습니다
with video evidence suggesting that Mr. Park's death,
동영상 증거 포함 박씨의 죽음을 암시하며,
which shocked the nation, was ordered by the WR family.
국민을 충격에 빠트린, WR 가족이 주문했습니다.
WR Entertainment director
WR 엔터테인먼트 디렉터
- Hey! - and spouse of the Chairman, Ms. Lee...
- 여기요! - 그리고 이 회장의 배우자...
What the hell happened with the Son Guk Won story?
도대체 무슨 일이 일어난 걸까 손국원 이야기요?
You useless piece of shit!
이 쓸모없는 놈아!
- Overseeing multiple subsidiaries... - Middleman broker, MeTuber Mr. Choi...
- 여러 자회사 감독... - 중개인, 미튜버 최씨...
WR Entertainment director...
WR 엔터테인먼트 디렉터...
A chaebol family's shocking true colors have been laid bare.
재벌가의 충격적인 본색 드러났습니다.
This murder-for-hire also leads back to WR Group...
이번 살인도 역시 WR 그룹으로 다시 연결됩니다...
Ms. Lee, a director at WR Entertainment and the wife of the chairman...
Ms. 이씨 WR Entertainment 이사 그리고 회장 부인...
WR is at the center of this...
이것의 중심에는 WR이 있습니다...
There are still more cases yet to surface...
아직 드러나지 않은 사례가 더 있습니다...
Tonight at nine...
오늘 밤 9시...
She's coming out!
그녀가 나오고 있어요!
There she is!
저기 있어요!
Let go of me!
날 놔줘!
Get your hands off me!
나한테서 손 떼세요!
Any comment?
의견이 있으신가요?
Let go of me!
날 놔줘!
Democracy is dead in this country!
이 나라 민주주의는 죽었어!
I'm being framed!
난 누명을 쓰고 있어요!
- Why did you kill Park Jae Sang? - Get off me!
- 박재상을 왜 죽였나요? - 나한테서 떨어져!
Let go!
가자!
This is a witch hunt!
이건 마녀사냥이다!
Get off!
내리세요!
From in there.
거기서.
Enjoy your stay. A nice, long one.
즐거운 시간 보내세요. 멋지고 긴 것입니다.
You little...
너 꼬마...
You're dead! You hear me?
넌 죽었어! 내 말 들려?
MeTuber Mr. Choi has been
MeTuber 최 씨는
on Ms. Lee Yang Mi's payroll since last year,
이양미씨 작년부터 급여
[MeTuber Choi Arrested This Afternoon] pumping out vicious rumors and fake stories...
[최미유튜버 오늘 오후에 체포] 악랄한 소문과 가짜 이야기를 퍼뜨리는 중...
Considering the circumstances around Oh Kwang Jae's murder
상황을 고려하여 오광재 살해 당시
[Charged with Spreading Rumors on Orders] and the allegations
[주문 관련 루머 유포 혐의] 그리고 혐의
tying Chairman Kwon Se Myeong to it,
권세명 회장을 거기에 묶어
evidence now shows they've been running
이제 증거에 따르면 그들이 실행되고 있었다
a systematic campaign of media manipulation and cover-ups
체계적인 캠페인 미디어 조작 및 은폐
- I only did what she ordered. - to bury the WR family's dirty secrets.
- 나는 그녀가 시키는 대로만 했어요. - WR 가족의 더러운 비밀을 묻기 위해.
Prosecutors believe this is just the tip of the iceberg,
검찰은 믿는다 이것은 빙산의 일각에 불과합니다.
[Chairman Kwon Tied to Oh Kwang Jae Case?] and that even more high-profile figures
[권회장은 오광재 사건과 연관돼 있다?] 그리고 훨씬 더 주목받는 인물
[Singer Jung Yun Seo, Actress Ryu Ji Eun] are suspected of illegal involvement
[가수 정윤서, 배우 류지은] 불법 개입 혐의
[Ondam Hotel: The "Entertainment" Protocol] with aspiring entertainers.
[온담호텔: "엔터테인먼트" 프로토콜] 야심찬 연예인들과 함께
They intend to widen the investigation.
그들은 조사를 확대할 계획입니다.
Mr. Nam, who was locked up last April for the murder of rookie actress Ms. Hwang,
미스터. 지난 4월 구속된 남 씨 신인배우 황씨 살해 용의자
has been cleared of all charges and walked free this morning after ten months.
모든 혐의가 면제되었습니다 그리고 10개월 만에 오늘 아침에 자유로워졌습니다.
Petit! Petit! Petit!
쁘띠! 쁘띠! 쁘띠!
My man, Tae Seop!
내남자 태섭!
I knew you had it in you.
나는 당신이 그것을 가지고 있다는 것을 알았습니다.
I already made sure the prosecutors throw at least twenty years at Lee Yang Mi,
검찰이 던지는 걸 이미 확인했어 이양미에서 최소 20년은
so relax, all right?
그러니 진정해, 알았지?
And Father looks like he'll check out right on schedule.
그리고 아버지는 그럴 것 같아 일정에 맞춰 바로 확인하세요.
From here on, it's just us. We back each other up and rise together.
여기서부터는 우리뿐이에요. 우리는 서로를 지지하고 함께 일어섭니다.
Right.
오른쪽.
Funny how the timing lined up so perfectly, isn't it?
타이밍이 너무 완벽하게 맞춰진 게 웃기네요. 그렇지 않나요?
The timing was so perfect,
타이밍이 너무 완벽했어요
I did a deep dive into WR Hospital,
WR 병원에 대해 자세히 알아봤습니다.
where your father's doctor works.
네 아버지의 주치의가 일하는 곳.
[VIP Ward Medical Inventory Ledger]
[VIP 병동 의료재고 대장]
See right there?
바로 저기 보이나요?
Aspirin, ordered regularly, all on your instructions.
정기적으로 주문하는 아스피린, 모두 당신의 지시에 따릅니다.
Aspirin is basically poison for someone with kidney failure.
아스피린은 기본적으로 독이다 신장 장애가 있는 사람을 위해.
So why was it being ordered like clockwork?
그렇다면 왜 시계처럼 주문되었습니까?
When the Chairman dies, they'll do an autopsy.
회장이 사망하면 부검을 할 예정이다.
Aspirin shows up in the toxicology,
아스피린은 독성학에 등장합니다.
but there's nothing on the chart.
하지만 차트에는 아무것도 없어요.
That's malpractice
그건 부정행위야
and murder by proxy, isn't it?
그리고 대리 살인도 하는 거 아닌가요?
- Look, just hear me out. - You know,
- 이봐, 내 말 좀 들어봐. - 있잖아,
you might actually end up
넌 실제로 끝날 수도 있어
outlasting your pretty stepmother behind bars.
철창 뒤에서 예쁜 계모보다 오래가는 것.
I thought you were an idiot...
난 당신이 바보인줄 알았는데...
but you turned the family doctor and tried to kill your own father.
하지만 당신은 가정의를 바꾸었어요 그리고 네 아버지를 죽이려고 했어.
What the hell? This isn't some medieval dynasty.
대체 뭐야? 이것은 중세 왕조가 아닙니다.
All for that WR throne,
WR 왕좌를 위해 모두
you really outdid yourself. I'll give you that.
당신은 정말로 자신을 능가했습니다. 내가 그걸 줄게.
Oh, come on...
아, 어서...
WR's already on your side,
WR은 이미 당신 편이에요,
so why are you pulling this?
그럼 왜 이걸 당기는 건데?
I'm the one who's taking you
너를 데려가는 사람은 바로 나야
all the way to the Blue House. So what is your problem?
청와대까지. 그렇다면 당신의 문제는 무엇입니까?
Deep down, you know
깊은 곳에서는, 알잖아
how incompetent you are better than anyone else.
당신은 얼마나 무능한가 누구보다 낫습니다.
You'll turn WR into a house of cards.
WR을 카드 하우스로 바꿔보세요.
I finally have WR under my heel.
마침내 내 발뒤꿈치 아래에 WR이 생겼습니다.
I'm not about to watch it crumble.
나는 그것이 무너지는 것을 보고 싶지 않습니다.
- You piece of shit. - No.
- 이 똥같은 놈아. - 아니요.
That's not it!
그게 아니야!
Choose carefully.
신중하게 선택하세요.
Spend the rest of your life rotting in a cell
남은 인생을 감방에서 썩어가며 보내세요
as the man who killed his own father,
자기 아버지를 죽인 사람으로서
or hold on to whatever's left
아니면 남은 것을 붙잡으세요
of that empty throne.
그 빈 왕좌의.
Sir.
선생님.
From now on, every single decision about this Group
지금부터, 이 그룹에 대한 모든 결정
goes through me.
나를 통과합니다.
Petit.
쁘띠.
The real owner of WR
WR의 실제 소유자
just changed.
방금 바뀌었어요.
Standing where I've always dreamed of standing,
항상 꿈꿔왔던 곳에 서 있는 것,
so many faces flood back.
너무 많은 얼굴이 되돌아옵니다.
Oh Kwang Jae, who pushed me into this world
나를 이 세상에 밀어준 오광재
and plunged straight into hell,
그리고 곧바로 지옥으로 떨어졌습니다.
and the revolting eyes
그리고 역겨운 눈
of every man who held the power.
권력을 보유한 모든 사람의
[Four Seasons]
[사계절]
I'd like to thank the trash reporters
쓰레기 기자들에게 감사의 말씀을 전하고 싶습니다
who used their precious little fingers
소중한 작은 손가락을 사용한 사람
to manufacture my life.
내 삶을 만들어가기 위해.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
And
그리고
to Director Lee Yang Mi,
이양미 감독님께
who ripped out my beating heart and left me with nothing but agony,
내 뛰는 심장을 찢어버린 그 사람 그리고 나에게 고통만 남겼습니다.
my sincerest thanks.
진심으로 감사드립니다.
That we were able to climb this far
우리가 여기까지 오를 수 있었다는 것
is all thanks to your petty rage
모두 너의 사소한 분노 덕분이다
and your dirty tricks.
그리고 당신의 더러운 속임수
And
그리고
to Bang Tae Seop, who never threw me away, never let me die,
방태섭에게, 나를 버린 적이 없고, 내가 죽게 두지 않은 사람,
even when I was just his shield, and stood by me all the way here.
내가 그의 방패였을 때도 그리고 여기까지 내 옆에 서 있었어요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
What were we even bleeding for,
우리는 무엇 때문에 피를 흘리고 있었던 걸까요,
dragging ourselves,
우리 자신을 끌고
all the way here?
여기까지요?
Why did we have to survive
우리는 왜 살아남아야 했나
every single one of those moments?
매 순간마다요?
Through every one
모든 것을 통해
of these impossible trials,
불가능한 시도 중
the reason I never gave up and made it to this stage
내가 결코 포기하지 않은 이유 그리고 이 단계에 이르렀어요
is them.
그들입니다.
I dedicate this honor
이 영광을 바칩니다
to them.
그들에게.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Congratulations.
축하합니다.
Chu Sang Ah.
추상아.
Make sure everything stays on track.
모든 것이 제대로 진행되는지 확인하세요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
But you know what?
하지만 그거 알아요?
Aren't you a little too young to be Senior Secretary for Civil Affairs?
좀 너무 어리지 않나요? 민정수석비서관이 되려면?
Well, nobody said old politics makes for good politics.
글쎄, 아무도 말하지 않았어 오래된 정치가 좋은 정치를 만든다.
Just like this script right here.
바로 여기 이 스크립트와 같습니다.
My fellow citizens,
시민 여러분,
and members of the press,
및 언론인
today marks the 100th day of our new administration.
오늘이 100일이에요 새 행정부의.
I'm here to reflect on where we may have fallen short.
나는 반성하기 위해 여기 있다 우리가 부족한 부분에 대해.
And to recommit ourselves to our mission.
그리고 우리의 사명을 다시 다짐하는 것입니다.
One-second pause.
1초 동안 정지합니다.
[Blue House, Republic of Korea]
[대한민국 청와대]
45 degrees right.
오른쪽 45도.
And smile.
그리고 미소를 지으세요.
First.
첫 번째.
I'd like to express my gratitude to the people.
국민 여러분께 감사의 말씀을 전하고 싶습니다.
Thanks to your unwavering support,
여러분의 변함없는 지지에 감사드립니다.
we've been able to govern without disruption.
우리는 중단 없이 통치할 수 있었습니다.
With the Seoam mayoral race just ten days out,
서암시장 선거가 열흘 앞으로 다가온 가운데
[Doyak's Bang Tae Seop on the Trail] former Senior Secretary Bang Tae Seop
[트레일을 달리는 도약의 방태섭] 방태섭 전 수석비서관
is leading in the polls.
이 여론조사에서 선두를 달리고 있습니다.
After spearheading sweeping reforms of prosecution and law enforcement,
대대적인 개혁을 주도한 후 검찰 및 법 집행 기관의
Candidate Bang's approval has soared,
방 후보 지지율이 치솟았는데
and he's not just the frontrunner for Seoam Mayor,
그리고 그는 단순한 선두주자가 아닙니다 서암시장님께,
[Youth Support Fuels Presidential Buzz] he's already being talked about
[청년 지원이 대통령 화제를 불러일으킨다] 그 사람에 대해서는 이미 화제가 되고 있습니다
as a serious contender for the presidency.
대통령직에 대한 진지한 경쟁자로서.
One last question.
마지막 질문입니다.
What does Chu Sang Ah mean to you?
추상아는 당신에게 어떤 의미인가요?
My wife and I have fought through
아내와 나는 이겨냈어
countless hardships together.
수많은 고난을 함께 합니다.
For someone who still has a long road ahead,
아직 갈 길이 멀다면
she's my one and only ally.
그녀는 내 유일한 동맹자야.
[Doyak Party, Bang Tae Seop] We need to head in. Let's wrap it here.
[도약당, 방태섭] 들어가야 합니다. 여기서 마무리하겠습니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Oh, by the way, did you hear about the WR family?
아, 그런데, WR 가족에 대해 들어보셨나요?
[WR Chairman Kwon Regains Consciousness, Signaling Return]
[WR 권 회장 의식 회복, 신호 반환]
[Second son Kwon Jong Il rumored to return, replacing Director Lee Yang Mi]
[둘째 권정일이 돌아온다는 소문이 돌았는데, 이양미 감독 교체]
WR Group Chairman Kwon Se Myeong, one of Korea's biggest names in business,
WR그룹 권세명 회장, 한국의 비즈니스계 최고 명사 중 한 명,
has reportedly woken up after his long fight with illness.
일어났다고 합니다 오랜 병마와 싸운 끝에.
There are also reports that his second son, Kwon Jong Il,
보고서도 있습니다 그의 둘째 아들인 권정일은
is stepping back into management,
경영진으로 복귀 중입니다.
and all eyes are on WR Group's leadership shakeup.
그리고 모든 눈은 WR 그룹의 리더십 개편에 대해.
[Director Lee Yang Mi to be Released via Special Pardon on the 20th]
[이양미 감독이 공개된다. 20일 특사를 통해]
[Caller ID Restricted]
[발신번호 표시 제한]
This is Cheongseong Penitentiary.
청성교도소입니다.
This call may be monitored.
이 통화는 모니터링될 수 있습니다.
Chu Sang Ah.
추상아.
I'll be seeing you
곧 만나요
very soon.
곧.
[Waiting Room: Chu Sang Ah]
[대기실 : 추상아]
Sang Ah.
상아.
Sang Ah, stay with me.
상아야, 내 옆에 있어줘.
Sang Ah!
상아!
Where am I?
나는 어디에 있습니까?
Are you with me?
당신은 나와 함께 있습니까?
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Is this hell?
여기가 지옥인가요?
Yeah...
응...
It's hell.
그것은 지옥이다.
Ladies and gentlemen, the moment you've been waiting for.
신사숙녀 여러분, 당신이 기다려온 순간입니다.
Please welcome Candidate Bang Tae Seop
방태섭 후보님을 환영해 주십시오
and his lifelong partner,
그리고 그의 평생 파트너
actress Chu Sang Ah!
배우 추상아!
[To our climax: shattered, but never broken]
[우리의 절정에 이르기까지: 부서졌지만 결코 깨지지 않았습니다]